Computer Programmer

ROBERT SMITH

Phone: (123) 456 78 99 Email: info@qwikresume.com Website: www.gwikresume.com

LinkedIn:

linkedin.com/qwikresume Address: 1737 Marshville Road,

Alabama.

Objective

Technically sophisticated Computer Programmer professional with 16 years of experience in the Technology domain, withsolid track record of efficient computer programming, database administration, human resource administration, and leadership skills. Powerful communicator, manager and problem solver who motivates teamwork and possesses the initiative to meet and exceed the demands of enthusiastic human resource, IT, data entry, and other related administrative objectives.

Skills

Microsoft Office, Oracle, Java, C++, Networking, Html, Sql, APEX, ADP Etc.

Work Experience

Computer Programmer

Cyberdata Technologies, Inc - April 2006 - December 2016

- Independently performed work in the support of the Mslabs Information Technology department.
- Responsible for the accuracy and quality of all data associated with each survey cruise using various database programs as Dbase, Oracle application express, SQL developer and Access.
- Tracked the data from the different surveys for processing into the master database.
- Collected, analyzed, managed and performed the work necessary to support the field party chiefs and unit personnel.
- Managed the data in various formats as flat files, Dbase, Access and Oracle, etc.
- Ability and knowledge to use structured query language, database triggers and functions
 procedures. Helped in some capacity and the beginning of the it unit trying to develop a new
 data tracking program and system with oracle application express.
- Knowledge of software life cycle including the source control and testing software an deployment with databasing.

Computer Programmer

ABC Corp - 2001 - 2006

- Coded and tested the programming for the in-house database.
- Debugged the code for existing programs.
- Balanced Workday between multiple projects and responded immediately to tech support requests from the Senior Staff.
- Reported issues and concerns immediately to the IT manager.
- Troubleshoot system bugs and issues.
- Ensuredthe code is error-free, readable, efficient, and logically organized for ease of access.
- · Updated and expanded the existing programs.

Education

Accounting/Data-Processing - August 1983 to December 1986(University Of Southern Mississippi Hattiesburg - Hattiesburg, MS)Summer Course Work: in Accounting I, Principles Of Finance, Business Law - June 1983 to July 1983(MGCCC)Accounting/Data-Processing - July 1983(Mississippi Gulf Coast Community College Gautier - Gautier, MS)High School Diploma - May 1983(Ocean Springs High School - Ocean Springs, MS)